https://www.feadog.ie/privacy-policy/

1. Privacy and your Personal Data
1.1 Feadog Teoranta (trading as ‘Feadog’) is committed to protecting the privacy of our users and customers. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you on how we gather, define and utilise your Information (as defined below).
1.2 It applies to any information collected by us or provided by you, whether from a purchase you made from our website www.feadog.ie or in any other way (such as over the telephone). It is also intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using our website and our products. Please take a minute to read and understand the policy.
1.3 All your personal information shall be held and used in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”) and national laws implementing GDPR and any legislation that replaces it in whole or in part and any other legislation relating to the protection of personal data. If you want to know what information we collect and hold about you or to exercise any of your rights as set out in section 9 below, please write to us at the below address or via e-mail at whistles@feadog.ie:
Feadog Teoranta, Unit 8, The Westway Centre, Ballymount Avenue, Walkinstown, Dublin 12, Republic of Ireland
1.4 Feadog Teoranta is the controller of your information for the purposes of the GDPR.
2. What Information do we collect on our website?
2.1 When you visit our Website (including the mobile optimised version of the website accessible from your portable hand-held device) you may provide us with personal information such as name, address, email address, mobile phone number, date of birth, etc. You may provide us with information in a number of ways:
a) by supplying us with the Information as listed above, on an individual basis by registering as a registered user or subscribing to receive updates or offers from us. To become a registered user you must provide us with your name, postcode, date of birth and email address, but you may also provide us with additional information if you choose to do so.
b) by corresponding with us by email, in which case we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses;
c) by making a purchase on www.feadog.ie and;
d) through any preferences and areas of interest as advised by you on subscribing to our e-letter via Facebook on the Sign Up forum.
2.2 We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system, browser type and the geographical location of your computer, for system administration purposes. We may create a statistical data report about browsing actions and patterns and does not identify you as an individual.
3. How we use your Information
3.1 We will hold, use and disclose your information for our legitimate business purposes including:
a) to keep you up to date about important changes to our business;
b) to direct-market products and services, advise you of news and industry updates, events, promotions and competitions and other information. Before we do so, you will be given an option to opt-out of such communications and an option to unsubscribe will also be provided with each communication;
c) to apply profiling technology which analyses our customers’ engagement with our direct marketing communications, activity and interests so that we can send you content that is relevant to you;
d) to answer your queries;
e) to release Information to regulatory or law enforcement agencies, if we are required or permitted to do so.
3.2 We may process certain sensitive personal data (known as special category data in GDPR) where you include it in information you send to us. We have processes in place to limit our use and disclosure of such sensitive data other than where permitted by law.
4. What Information do we collect from you?
4.1 When you purchase an item from Feadog, we may collect your details to process your order and to improve our service to you. These details will never be shared with a third party and will be held securely in our database. Details we may collect from you include:
a) your name, date of birth, email address, and geological location. Note: Your credit card details are passed on immediately for payment processing; we never receive or store your credit card details anywhere on our servers.
5. The legal basis for processing your Information
5.1 Under GDPR, the main grounds that we rely upon in order to process your Information are the following:
a) Necessary for compliance with a legal obligation – we are subject to certain legal requirements which may require us to process your information. We may also be obliged by law to disclose your information to a regulatory body or law enforcement agency;
b) Necessary for the purposes of legitimate interests – either we, or a third party, will need to process your Information for the purposes of our (or a third party’s) legitimate interests, provided we have established that those interests are not overridden by your rights and freedoms, including your right to have your Information protected. Our legitimate interests include responding to requests and enquiries from you or a third party, fulfilling gift card sales, optimising our website and customer experience, informing you about our products and services and ensuring that our operations are conducted in an appropriate and efficient manner;
c) Consent – in some circumstances, we may ask for your consent to process your Information in a particular way.
6. How we share your Information
6.1 In certain circumstances we will share your Information with other parties. Details of those parties are set out below along with the reasons for sharing it.
a) Regulatory and law enforcement agencies. As noted above, if we receive a request from a regulatory body or law enforcement agency, and if permitted under GDPR and other laws, we may disclose certain personal information to such bodies or agencies.
b) Fulfilment companies. We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mails, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments and providing customer services. Such companies and individuals will have access to personal information needed to perform these functions, but may not use it for any other purposes and are required to process the data in accordance with the Irish Data Protection Act 1988. 19.
c) Payment companies. The Feadóg.ie payment pages use encryption technology to provide security of payments. The user agrees that the payment information provided by him may be held by Feadóg Teoranta and may only be given to payment partners (such as a bank) and only to any other party with the users express permission (save where the laws of the citizenship, domicile or residence of the user prohibit such information). Credit card payments are processed by Realex via their own web site and payment processing system. The credit card details are not made available at any time to Feadóg Teoranta.
6.2 Apart from the above, any non-public personal information that you may provide via our sites will be used solely for the purpose stated on the page where it is collected. Feadóg Teoranta will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of Feadóg Teoranta and its affiliated companies unless (a) expressly authorized by you, (b) necessary to enable Feadóg Teoranta contractors or agents to perform certain functions for us, or (c) required or permitted by law. In all cases, we will disclose the information consistent with applicable laws and regulations and we will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose it was provided.
7. How long we hold your Information
We will only retain your information for as long as is necessary for the purpose or purposes for which we have collected it. The criteria that we use to determine retention periods will be determined by the nature of the data and the purposes for which it is kept. For example, if we receive your information through a competition entry, we will retain your data for as long as is necessary to administer the competition. If we receive your information when you apply for a job, we will retain your data for as long as is necessary to process your application and maintain application statistics. In certain circumstances, once we have deleted or anonymised your data, we may need to retain parts of it (for example, your email address), in order to comply with our obligations under GDPR or other legislation, or for fraud detection purposes.
8. Your rights relating to your Information
8.1 You have certain rights in relation to personal information we hold about you. Details of these rights and how to exercise them are set out below. We will require evidence of your identity before we are able to act on your request.
a) Right of Access. You have the right at any time to ask us for a copy of the Information about you that we hold, and to confirm the nature of the Information and how it is used. Where we have good reason, and if the GDPR permits, we can refuse your request for a copy of your Information, or certain elements of the request. If we refuse your request or any element of it, we will provide you with our reasons for doing so.
b) Right of Correction or Completion. If Information we hold about you is not accurate, or is out of date or incomplete, and requires amendment or correction you have a right to have the data rectified, updated or completed. You can let us know by contacting us at the address or email address set out above.
c) Right of Erasure. In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that Information we hold about you is erased e.g. if the Information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed or our processing of the Information is based on your consent and there are no other legal grounds on which we may process the Information.
d) Right to Object to or Restrict Processing. In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to our processing of your Information by contacting us at the address or email address set out above. For example, if we are processing your Information on the basis of our legitimate interests and there are no compelling legitimate grounds for our processing which override your rights and interests. You also have the right to object to use of your Information for direct marketing purposes.
You may also have the right to restrict our use of your Information, such as in circumstances where you have challenged the accuracy of the Information and during the period where we are verifying its accuracy.
e) Right of Data Portability. In certain instances, you have a right to receive any Information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You can ask us to transmit that Information to you or directly to a third party organisation.
This right exists in respect of information that:
• you have provided to us previously; and
• is processed by us using automated means.
While we are happy for such requests to be made, we are not able to guarantee technical compatibility with a third party organisation’s systems. We are also unable to comply with requests that relate to information of others without their consent.
8.2 You can exercise any of the above rights by contacting us at the address or e-mail address set out above. You can exercise your rights free of charge.
8.3 Most of the above rights are subject to limitations and exceptions. We will provide reasons if we are unable to comply with any request for the exercise of your rights.
9. Consent
To the extent that we are processing your information based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can do this by unsubscribing via the link provided in any direct marketing communication, or contacting us at the address or email address set out above.
10. Cookies
10.1 You should also be aware that when you visit our websites, we collect certain information that does not identify you personally, but provides us with “usage data,” such as the number of visitors we receive or what pages are visited most often. This data helps us to analyse and improve the usefulness of the information we provide at these websites.
Similar to other commercial websites, our Website uses a technology called “cookies” and web server logs to collect information about how our Website is used. A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies
10.2 Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our website, and the websites visited just before and just after our website.
10.3 Cookies, in conjunction with our web server’s log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our Website and which parts of the website are most popular. This helps us gather feedback so that we can improve our Website and better serve our customers. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal Information about you and we do not generally store any personal Information that you provided to us in your cookies.
10.4 We use ‘session’ cookies which enable you to carry information across pages of the Website and avoid having to re-enter information. Session cookies enable us to compile statistics that help us to understand how the Website is being used and to improve its structure.
10.5 We also use ‘persistent’ cookies which remain in the cookies file of your browser for longer and help us to recognise you as a unique visitor to the Website, tailoring the content of certain areas of the Website to offer you content that match your preferred interests.
11. Tags
We may also use what is known as “client-side page tagging”, which uses code on each page to write certain information about the page and the visitor to a log when a page is rendered by your web browser. This technique is also commonly used on commercial websites. “Tagging” does result in a JavaScript program running on your computer, but it is limited to providing information about the page that you are requesting and the configuration of your browser. It will not read any of your data files, or execute any additional programs. It does not extract any personal information about you, such as your name or address. You can prevent tagging by disabling JavaScript in your browser, but that may prevent you from using all of our website’s functions.
12. Website Accessibility
12.1 Feadog recognises the importance of providing a website that is accessible to everyone and is easy to use. This section outlines our ongoing commitment to making our online services accessible and explains some of the accessibility features of this website.
12.2 Website accessibility means that people with disabilities can use the website. More specifically, website accessibility means that people with disabilities can perceive, understand, navigate, and interact with the website, and that they can contribute to the website. Website accessibility also benefits others, including older people with changing abilities due to aging. (Quote from https://www.w3.org/WAI/intro/accessibility.php)
12.3 This website contains the following features which should help users make the website more accessible:
a) providing a sitemap;
b) every content and decorative image has the ability to have alternative text added so if images are disabled or not appearing the user can see read what the image is displaying;
c) tabbing through the website is organised in a logical top down left to right order;
d) clearly defined visible hover and focus (tab) state for each link;
e) the ability to jump to the main content on the page by by-passing the top menu when you use the keyboard;
f) HTML for lists, tables and quotes being coded correctly;
g) the ability to navigate around the site and access all functionality by only using the keyboard;
h) all fields and labels within forms including error messages, are clearly labelled and have the correct notations;
i) the visual contrast combination of text and background colours meet the correct ratio so all text is easily read; and
j) the website is readable when large size text is used in Internet Explorer
12.4 At Feadog we are committed to making our website accessible to as many abled and less abled people as possible. We will continue to review, test and modify our website for usability and accessibility issues using a combination of both manual and automated testing tools. These tools and techniques help us to aim towards meeting (where possible) the W3C guidelines as part of our ongoing commitment towards an accessible website.
13. Changes to our Privacy Policy
This privacy policy can be changed by us at any time. If we change our privacy policy in the future, we will advise you of material changes or updates to our privacy policy by e-mail, where we are holding your e-mail address.
14. Complaints
If you are unhappy about our use of your information, you can contact us at the address or e-mail address above. You are also entitled to lodge a complaint with the Irish Data Protection Commissioner’s Office using any of the below contact methods:
Telephone: +353 (0761) 104 800
Email: info@dataprotection.ie
Post: Office of the Data Protection Commissioner, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co.Laois, R32 AP23
Feadóg original Irish whistleThe Feadóg original Irish whistle has been and continues to be manufactured in Ireland since 1978 and is sold in many countries worldwide. The Feadóg Irish Tin Whistle is the ideal Irish gift for people of all ages!
Site Links
Home
About Us
Our Blog
Distributors
Contact us
My Account
Delivery
Privacy Policy
T + C's
8 The Westway Centre, Ballymount Avenue, Dublin 12, D12 E899+353 1 456 9533whistles@feadog.ie
Copyright © Feadóg Teoranta. Site by Intrade.
Back to top
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you consent to the use of cookies in accordance with our cookie policy.
OK, Got it
Select the fields to be shown. Others will be hidden. Drag and drop to rearrange the order.
ImageSKURatingPriceStockAvailabilityAdd to cartDescriptionContentWeightDimensionsAdditional informationAttributesCustom attributesCustom fields
Compare
